preventdisease.com 2018-09-08

# PreventDisease.com - Privacy Statement

## **

Privacy Statement

**

**  
Overview**  
PreventDisease.com operates under the following set of strict privacy principles: 

  * The only information PreventDisease.com obtains about individual visitors to its Web site is that supplied voluntarily by visitors. 
  * Once registered as a member, PreventDisease.com representatives will NEVER request for your personal information, usernames or passwords via email and any attempt at such a request should be disregarded and ignored by any member.  

  * In cases when PreventDisease.com may need personal information to provide visitors with customized content or to inform them about new features or services, visitors are explicitly asked for that information. 
  * Personally identifiable information provided by visitors (name, e-mail or home address, etc.) will not be disclosed to ANYONE, including any outside organizations, associations, corporations or institutions unless visitors indicate that PreventDisease.com may do so. 
  * Only statistical information about our visitors as a group (usage habits, demographics) may be shared with any partner of PreventDisease.com. Personally identifiable information will not be shared at any time without the visitor's permission. PreventDisease.com employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions; personal information is stored in a secured database and always sent via an encrypted Internet channel. 
  * We will notify our users if we make significant changes to our privacy policy that may affect the use of health-related information, and we will obtain consent from consumers for any new uses of that data.

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: PreventDisease.com. 

**IP Addresses**  
An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. All computer identification on the Internet is conducted with IP addresses, which allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with each other. PreventDisease.com collects IP addresses in order to conduct system administration, report aggregate information to sponsors and advertisers, and to conduct site analysis. If a visitor requests pages from PreventDisease.com, the PreventDisease.com servers enter the visitor's IP address into a log. To maintain visitor anonymity, PreventDisease.com does not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. However, PreventDisease.com will use IP addresses to identify any visitors who refuse to comply with PreventDisease.com's in-house rules or terms of service, and to identify visitors who threaten our service, site, customers or others. 

**Cookies**  
Our site places a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard disk for record keeping purposes. Our site uses cookies during your online session to deliver content specific to your interests. Cookies allow us to avoid showing you the same ad or other message repeatedly. Our cookies do not contain personal information. They do enable PreventDisease.com to relate your use of the site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided to our site. 

**Registration**  
Our site's member registration system requires users to give us contact information such as their name and e-mail address. The user's contact information may be used to contact the visitor when necessary. **The user acknowledges that the member registration email address provided, automatically entitles and enlists the user to our free monthly newsletter as provided by our PD team.** The user can remove (opt-out) their email manually through any page on our website. If at any time users have been unsubscribed from the mailing list, they may also choose to add (opt-in) their email to receive future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below for further options. 

**External Links**  
In order to provide visitors with greater value, PreventDisease.com may provide links to various third party Web sites. However, even if a third-party affiliation exists between PreventDisease.com and that destination site, PreventDisease.com exercises no authority over linked sites, each of which maintains independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. PreventDisease.com assumes no responsibility or liability for these independent methods or actions and is not responsible for the independent policies or procedures of destination sites. Similarly, PreventDisease.com cannot take responsibility for the privacy initiatives or the content of such Web sites. These destination links are provided only for your convenience, and as such, you access them at your own risk. However, PreventDisease.com wishes to ensure the integrity of the PreventDisease.com Web site and its destination links, so any comments pertaining to the PreventDisease.com Web site or any sites accessed through PreventDisease.com links are greatly appreciated. 

**Community Partners**  
PreventDisease.com Community Partners represent well-respected healthcare organizations across the country. Through these partnerships, PreventDisease.com provides its Web site content and services to enhance the Web sites of our Community Partners. These sites also offer information about local healthcare resources, thereby helping members of their communities take active steps towards improving or maintaining their health. 

**Surveys and Questionnaires**  
Our online surveys and questionnaires may ask visitors for contact and demographic information. The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis, but it does not indicate the identity of individual users. 

**Contests**  
We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact and demographic information. The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may choose to receive future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. This information is shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis, but it does not indicate the identity of individual users. 

**Public Forums**  
PreventDisease.com provides its users with chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**  
The PreventDisease.com Web site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. PreventDisease.com employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions; personal information is stored in a secured database. 

**Children's Guidelines**  
Some sections of PreventDisease.com may be designed specifically for use by children under the age of 16. Contact information such as their name and e-mail address, and demographic information such as their ZIP code or age may be requested in those sections. In such cases, children will be notified that they should obtain permission from their parents before providing such information. 

PreventDisease.com does not disclose personally identifiable information about users under 16, whether or not an approval is obtained. Information about users under the age of 16 may be shared with third parties on an aggregate basis. Parents and those permitting minors to use the PreventDisease.com Web site should be aware that any information voluntarily given by children in chat sessions, e-mail exchanges, BBS's, forums, etc., may be used by third parties to generate unsolicited mail or other contact with children. 

**Choice/Opt-In**  
Our site gives users the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from us at the point where the user registers for a membership. 

**This site also gives users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to stop receiving communications or our service. Choose one of the following three options to successfully remove your email from our mailing lists:**

  1. You can unsubscribe your email from the left side interface of any page on our website under "Free Newsletter" and by inputting your email address, selecting the "Unsubscribe" radio button and clicking the "Go"button.
  2. You can send e-mail to  [yourprivacy@preventdisease.com](mailto:yourprivacy@preventdisease.com)
  3. You can send mail to the following postal address: 

Security and Privacy Dept.  
PreventDisease.com.  
P.O.Box 2087, SQ1 Stn  
100 City Centre Dr.  
Mississauga, ONT, L5B3C6  
Canada.

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Website, or your interaction with this Website, contact: 

Security and Privacy Dept.  
PreventDisease.com.  
P.O.Box 2087, SQ1 Stn  
100 City Centre Dr.  
Mississauga, ONT, L5B3C6  
Canada.  

**  
Online Service Agreement**  
Please see our [Online Service Agreement](https://www.preventdisease.com/home/terms_conditions.html) for other terms and conditions governing your use of the PreventDisease.com Web site. 

...............................................................................................................[](https://www.pinterest.com/pin/create/button/?url=https://www.preventdisease.com&media=https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7027/6851755809_df5b2051c9_z.jpg&description=Next%20stop:%20Pinterest)
